<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The humble and hearty representation and ingagement of the collective body of the city of London, and propounded by them to the free-commoners of the the counties, citties, townes and boroughs of the kingdome of England, and the dominion of Wales to, and with both Houses of Parliament, and each one to other.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1648</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B03716</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing H3396A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R188911</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">47012480</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 47012480</idno>
            <idno type="VID">174446</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B03716)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 174446)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2689:8)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The humble and hearty representation and ingagement of the collective body of the city of London, and propounded by them to the free-commoners of the the counties, citties, townes and boroughs of the kingdome of England, and the dominion of Wales to, and with both Houses of Parliament, and each one to other.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1648]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place and date of publication taken from Wing (2nd ed.)</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: University of London. Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Parliament --  17th century.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  Civil War, 1642-1649.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:174446:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 5 -->
            <head>The humble and hearty Repreſentation and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gagement of the Collective body of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and propounded by them to the Free-Commoners of all the Counties, Citties, Townes and Boroughs of the Kingdome of <hi>England,</hi> and the Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> to, and with both Houſes of PARLIAMENT, and each one to other.</head>
            <p>WEE cannot but deplore the ſad Condition of this lately floriſhing Kingdome, which by the ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſion of ſo much Engliſh blood allready ſhed, and the expence of loſſe of ſo many millions of Treaſure, the preſent commotions in ſome Counties, the imminent danger of the invaſion of Forrainers, (and thereby more great and bloody Warres aſſuredly to enſue) together with the general unſettlednes and unſatisfiedneſſe of the whole Kingdome, which do all threaten the irrecoverable Plun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging of this poore Kingdome into the bottomleſſe Gulfe of deſpaire and ruine.</p>
            <p>All which was we muſt attribute chiefly and before all things to the many crying ſins, of which this whole King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome, hath been guilty, juſtly provoking God to be angry with us, and thus ſeverely to chaſtice us<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> that we may be humbled under his Mighty hand: ſo we cannot but obſerve thoſe manifeſt and more mediate cauſes of this our great afflictions, which we can attribute to nothing ſo much and more obvious and apparent, Then to the great diſtance and miſunderſtanding, which now for many yeares, hath continued betwixt his Majeſty and the two Houſes of Parliament; The happy compoſing of which we with patience continue to expect in Gods good time to ſee effected: and now much the rather are our hopes quickned, our hearts cheared, and we refreſhed, that (notwithſtanding the late Votes of both Houſes of no addreſſe to his Majeſty, nor of his Majeſty to them, (which ſtrook us with extreame amazement) we perceive God hath affected your hearts, not only to Vote an Addreſſe to his Majeſty, but alſo to intend a perſonall Treaty with Him, the only probable way (under God that we know of) to effect a perfect good underſtanding, Vnion and agreement betwixt his Majeſty and you (ſo much deſired by all) and ſo to reſtore once more the bleſſed voice of Peace to this now languiſhing and dyeing Kingdome.</p>
            <p>And as to ſo good a work, we doubt not, but you have the concurrent wiſhes and hearty prayers of the Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerality of the Kingdom, we being confident that the hundreth man, that hath a conſiderable intereſt, in the ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther reall of perſonall, in the Kingdome, but from his ſoule deſires it, and will in no ſort oppoſe it, yet becauſe we underſtand that there wants not ſome who having ſome, preſent power in their hands; doe intend and are very likely to the utmoſt of their ability to impede and hinder you in ſo good a worke.</p>
            <p>We crave leave to let you know, that what you have don or ſhall hereafter do, in order to a perſonall Treaty with his Majeſty &amp; to the perfecting of an agreement betwixt him and you, ſhall not only be received by us with all humble and affectionate acknowledgement. But alſo we doe ſolemnely promiſe and engage our ſelves, as in the preſence of Almighty God, to, and with you, and each one to other, that we will to the utmoſt hazard of our lives and fortunes, maintaine, aſſiſt and defend you in it againſt all perſons whatſoever, enemies to the ſaid perſonall Treaty and Peace.</p>
            <p>We have nothing further to beg of you. But conclude with our hearty prayers to God for you, that be would eſtabliſh and confirme you in thoſe wayes of Peace, into which we hope you are with ſincerity now entered: That ſo you may have the honour to be the repairers of Breaches, and Reſtorers of Peace, and we the Comfort to ſit every one under our owne Vine and Figg Tree. Bleſsing you, and God for you, which that we may doe, ſhall ever be our prayers.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="notice">
            <p>All Free men in the City of LONDON, into whoſe hands this paper ſhall come, are requeſted to under write and ſend it forwards, that ſo it may be preſented to the Lord Mayor and Common Councell; and from them to the Honourable Houſes or Parliament. All Counties, Cities, Townes, Boroughs, and all Free-holders of this whole Kingdome are requeſted the ſame.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
